<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cmder on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/cmder/</link><description>Recent content in Cmder on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 05:46:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/cmder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrated Terminal Shortcut in VS Code Opens External Terminal</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/integrated-terminal-shortcut-in-vscode-opens-external-terminal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 05:46:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/integrated-terminal-shortcut-in-vscode-opens-external-terminal/</guid><description>For quite a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been slightly annoyed by the behaviour that the keyboard shortcut in Visual Studio Code didn&amp;rsquo;t open the integrated terminal if I also had an external terminal open, it was switching to that one instead.
Googling the problem didn&amp;rsquo;t help me come closer to an explanation, which I suspected had to do with the language/keyboard specific nature of this issue. As you can see in the image below, the default keyboard shortcut to open the integrated terminal on my machine is Ctrl + ö.</description></item><item><title>Making Cmder Findable by Windows Search</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/making-cmder-findable-by-windows-search/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/making-cmder-findable-by-windows-search/</guid><description>This is just a short reminder for myself. I just found myself reinstalling Windows and thus also my favourite console, Cmder. I didn’t remember what to do to make it findable by Windows search, so here’s how: 1. Add path to environment variable 2. Log off and on again 3. Voilà!</description></item><item><title>Lenovo X1 Carbon with Windows 10</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/lenovo-x1-carbon-with-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 09:59:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/lenovo-x1-carbon-with-windows-10/</guid><description>I have recently got the chance to upgrade my work computer from an old, heavy and ugly machine with almost no battery life and a terrible screen to something new and shiny. I ended up getting the third generation Lenovo X1 Carbon (unfortunately without touch screen for budget reasons). This is my experience so far of that machine running Windows 10.
figure.lazy {
display: none;
}
I really like the X1 Carbon.</description></item><item><title>Bundling resources from plug-ins in my WordPress theme</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bundling-resources-from-plug-ins-in-my-wordpress-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 20:02:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bundling-resources-from-plug-ins-in-my-wordpress-theme/</guid><description>Some time ago I got the idea to ramp up my skills in front-end web development and the tooling used outside my own world of SharePoint. I decided to create my own WordPress theme, but use as much of existing tooling and templates as I could.
Sage got my attention, so I downloaded that and started to look into its components. This was all new territory for me with Bower, Gulp, PHP, NodeJS and so on.</description></item></channel></rss>