<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberry Pi on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/raspberry-pi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 14:58:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 5 – Costs and Architecture Refection</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-5-costs-and-architecture-refection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 14:58:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-5-costs-and-architecture-refection/</guid><description>Having run my home office monitoring service for more than a month, I can now reflect back on the project. Even though I have an MSDN subscription trough work with a bunch of Azure credit included to spend every month, I decided to use a Pay-As-You-Go subscription for this project. I wanted to be sure that the services I used was available to me even if I would loose the MSDN subscription.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 3 – Sending Data to Cloud</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-3-sending-data-to-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:48:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-3-sending-data-to-cloud/</guid><description>In part 3 of my IoT exploration I connect my Raspberry Pi to Azure IoT Hub and create a NodeJS app that relays data from my Python program to Azure.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 2 – Raspberry Pi Sense HAT</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-2-raspberry-pi-sense-hat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 05:38:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-2-raspberry-pi-sense-hat/</guid><description>Continuing my Internet of Things journey from my earlier post My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure, I got a Raspberry Pi with a Sense HAT. The Sense HAT has all the features I need, integrated in one shield: temperature, humidity and barometric pressure and a LED as a bonus. Given my goal that I wanted to push the data to a hosted service, I now had a much better foundation for succeeding with that.</description></item><item><title>Difference between Arduino and Raspberry Pi for a High-Level Programmer</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/difference-between-arduino-and-raspberry-pi-for-a-high-level-programmer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 16:17:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/difference-between-arduino-and-raspberry-pi-for-a-high-level-programmer/</guid><description>Before I got an Arduino for Christmas I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about it. I had heard about Raspberry Pi though, and I was told that it was roughly the same thing.
It&amp;rsquo;s true that the two devices have some common characteristics, but to me the differences are fundamental. As someone who does high-level programming for a living, I am appealed by the idea of being able to read values from analogue sensors in my code, and the plethora of sensors available for the Arduino is impressive.</description></item></channel></rss>