<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 10:22:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Settings for new MacBook Pro</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/settings-for-new-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 10:22:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/settings-for-new-macbook-pro/</guid><description>I recently bought a new machine, a MacBook Pro 16&amp;quot;, and this is my initial configuration. I&amp;rsquo;m documenting this for my future self so I have something to cherry-pick from if I will ever configure a new Mac from scratch. Some of these things might not be relevant in future versions of macOS or for future versions of myself, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see a point in automating it.</description></item><item><title>Yamaha YAS-109 Soundbar has Excessive Network Traffic</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/yamaha-yas-109-soundbar-has-excessive-network-traffic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 11:30:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/yamaha-yas-109-soundbar-has-excessive-network-traffic/</guid><description>This is an appeal to any of you who is coding for, or otherwise developing connected devices, to put some extra thought into your network traffic. Maybe also a warning to consumers and an encouragement to us tech savvy people to monitor your connected devices.</description></item><item><title>I ❤️ My "New" 2013 MacBook Pro</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/i-love-my-new-2013-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 21:29:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/i-love-my-new-2013-macbook-pro/</guid><description>This is a story about my personal computer (PC) experience, from the 1990’s up to my new love for a six year old laptop.
In November 2019 my wife bought a new laptop (MacBook Air) and I took over the old one. It’s a 2013 MacBook Pro that I have borrowed a few times for debugging web pages on iOS, but beyond that I don’t have much macOS experience. I saw the opportunity to take it and learn macOS for real for the first time.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 2 – Raspberry Pi Sense HAT</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-2-raspberry-pi-sense-hat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 05:38:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-2-raspberry-pi-sense-hat/</guid><description>Continuing my Internet of Things journey from my earlier post My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure, I got a Raspberry Pi with a Sense HAT. The Sense HAT has all the features I need, integrated in one shield: temperature, humidity and barometric pressure and a LED as a bonus. Given my goal that I wanted to push the data to a hosted service, I now had a much better foundation for succeeding with that.</description></item><item><title>Difference between Arduino and Raspberry Pi for a High-Level Programmer</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/difference-between-arduino-and-raspberry-pi-for-a-high-level-programmer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 16:17:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/difference-between-arduino-and-raspberry-pi-for-a-high-level-programmer/</guid><description>Before I got an Arduino for Christmas I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about it. I had heard about Raspberry Pi though, and I was told that it was roughly the same thing.
It&amp;rsquo;s true that the two devices have some common characteristics, but to me the differences are fundamental. As someone who does high-level programming for a living, I am appealed by the idea of being able to read values from analogue sensors in my code, and the plethora of sensors available for the Arduino is impressive.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-1-the-failure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 17:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-1-the-failure/</guid><description>Last Christmas I got an Arduino starter kit for present. It took me a long time to finally open the box and have an idea about what I should do with it. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found challenging about learning new stuff that I don&amp;rsquo;t have an immediate use for, is the lack of a clear goal. Making an LED blink isn&amp;rsquo;t all that exiting in my mind and even though I like the projects in the starter kit, I didn&amp;rsquo;t do them until I had a project of my own figured out.</description></item><item><title>WinDock Configuration for my 21:9 Screen</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/windock-configuration-for-my-219-screen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 16:59:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/windock-configuration-for-my-219-screen/</guid><description>Hi have recently bought an ultra-wide monitor for my desk at home, a Dell U3415W. I&amp;rsquo;m using it both for work as a coder and for my personal needs such as photo editing, web browsing and watching films. I have previously used a dual monitor setup, so I wanted to find a way of organising windows to be used side-by-side in a productive manner.
figure.lazy {
display: none;
}
Dell U3415W Monitor, 34″ 3440×1440
Dell U3415W Monitor, 34″ 3440×1440
Of course Windows has had the feature to add two windows side-by-side built-in since Windows 7.</description></item><item><title>Inexpensive Home Media Solution</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/inexpensive-home-media-solution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 21:26:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/inexpensive-home-media-solution/</guid><description>As my Mac Mini from 2010 has gotten slower and slower I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about a replacement for it as the HTPC (Home Theatre Personal Computer) I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for. I was running Plex (both server and client) on it connected to a “dumb TV” and I&amp;rsquo;ve been fully happy with that. So, when I draw the conclusion that the old computer didn&amp;rsquo;t cut it any more, I had a few different options.</description></item><item><title>Lenovo X1 Carbon with Windows 10</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/lenovo-x1-carbon-with-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 09:59:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/lenovo-x1-carbon-with-windows-10/</guid><description>I have recently got the chance to upgrade my work computer from an old, heavy and ugly machine with almost no battery life and a terrible screen to something new and shiny. I ended up getting the third generation Lenovo X1 Carbon (unfortunately without touch screen for budget reasons). This is my experience so far of that machine running Windows 10.
figure.lazy {
display: none;
}
I really like the X1 Carbon.</description></item><item><title>Building a Mini-PC in 2014</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/building-a-mini-pc-in-2014/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 05:31:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/building-a-mini-pc-in-2014/</guid><description>Recently I helped my sister with a new computer. Her previous one was typical low-end desktop machine that you would find in any of the big stores. As such, it was bulky and with time had become very noisy. So when I took the &amp;ldquo;assignment&amp;rdquo; to find a new one I was looking for something configurable, smaller, with a decent value for money and something my sister would perceive as &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>