<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 14:02:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Asuswrt-Merlin Firmware Update Checker</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/asuswrt-merlin-firmware-update-checker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 14:02:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/asuswrt-merlin-firmware-update-checker/</guid><description>I have an Asus RT-AC68U router at home. I’ve previously used the build-in update checker together with a notification script that ran on the router itself. Recently I noticed that I hadn’t got any update notifications in a long time, one of the downsides of silent failures. This is my custom code that looks for updates.</description></item><item><title>Firmware Update Notifications for My Asus Router</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/firmware-update-notifications-for-my-asus-router/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 11:14:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/firmware-update-notifications-for-my-asus-router/</guid><description>Even though there is an app for my Asus RT-AC68U router with the default firmware, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked that well for me and I wanted reliable firmware update notifications. I found that this has been done by others, but still, there are a few steps to go through, so I&amp;rsquo;m documenting them here. This works for several other Asus router models as well, see the list of supported routers.
Installing Custom Firmware The first step I took was to install the custom firmware Asuswrt-Merlin.</description></item><item><title>Bypassing a Corporate Proxy</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bypassing-a-corporate-proxy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 09:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bypassing-a-corporate-proxy/</guid><description>Quite a few organisations seems to find this thing called “Internet” a scary thing that employees can only be given access to by grace of the mighty network administrators. As a consultant I have worked for a few of those organisations and felt the frustration when a blog is blocked or network traffic is so slow that you&amp;rsquo;d guess that it&amp;rsquo;s manually monitored before accepted. I would personally never try to bypass these controls of course, but hypothetically one could do like the following.</description></item></channel></rss>