<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tooling on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/categories/tooling/</link><description>Recent content in Tooling on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 21:34:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/categories/tooling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Favourite Note Taking App for Mac and iPhone</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-favourite-note-taking-app-for-mac-and-iphone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 21:34:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-favourite-note-taking-app-for-mac-and-iphone/</guid><description>After switching from Windows to Mac, I have reconsidered a few of the applications I use. To my own surprise I ended up with a paid one that’s only available on Apple devices – Bear.</description></item><item><title>Simple Short URL Service</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/simple-short-url-service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 14:45:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/simple-short-url-service/</guid><description>I happened to buy a domain name that could be used for short URL&amp;rsquo;s and thought – why not, let&amp;rsquo;s give it a try!</description></item><item><title>Asuswrt-Merlin Firmware Update Checker</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/asuswrt-merlin-firmware-update-checker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 14:02:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/asuswrt-merlin-firmware-update-checker/</guid><description>I have an Asus RT-AC68U router at home. I’ve previously used the build-in update checker together with a notification script that ran on the router itself. Recently I noticed that I hadn’t got any update notifications in a long time, one of the downsides of silent failures. This is my custom code that looks for updates.</description></item><item><title>MacOS Alternative to Notepad++</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/macos-alternative-to-notepad-plus-plus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 06:22:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/macos-alternative-to-notepad-plus-plus/</guid><description>Having switched from Windows to Mac quite recently, there is one application in particular that I’m missing – Notepad++. After trying Notes and Stickes, Brackets and a bunch of others, I had to rethink what I was actually using Notepad++ for and which characteristics I was appreciating the most.</description></item><item><title>Settings for new MacBook Pro</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/settings-for-new-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 10:22:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/settings-for-new-macbook-pro/</guid><description>I recently bought a new machine, a MacBook Pro 16&amp;quot;, and this is my initial configuration. I&amp;rsquo;m documenting this for my future self so I have something to cherry-pick from if I will ever configure a new Mac from scratch. Some of these things might not be relevant in future versions of macOS or for future versions of myself, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see a point in automating it.</description></item><item><title>I ❤️ My "New" 2013 MacBook Pro</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/i-love-my-new-2013-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 21:29:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/i-love-my-new-2013-macbook-pro/</guid><description>This is a story about my personal computer (PC) experience, from the 1990’s up to my new love for a six year old laptop.
In November 2019 my wife bought a new laptop (MacBook Air) and I took over the old one. It’s a 2013 MacBook Pro that I have borrowed a few times for debugging web pages on iOS, but beyond that I don’t have much macOS experience. I saw the opportunity to take it and learn macOS for real for the first time.</description></item><item><title>Firmware Update Notifications for My Asus Router</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/firmware-update-notifications-for-my-asus-router/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 11:14:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/firmware-update-notifications-for-my-asus-router/</guid><description>Even though there is an app for my Asus RT-AC68U router with the default firmware, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t worked that well for me and I wanted reliable firmware update notifications. I found that this has been done by others, but still, there are a few steps to go through, so I&amp;rsquo;m documenting them here. This works for several other Asus router models as well, see the list of supported routers.
Installing Custom Firmware The first step I took was to install the custom firmware Asuswrt-Merlin.</description></item><item><title>Integrated Terminal Shortcut in VS Code Opens External Terminal</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/integrated-terminal-shortcut-in-vscode-opens-external-terminal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 05:46:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/integrated-terminal-shortcut-in-vscode-opens-external-terminal/</guid><description>For quite a while I&amp;rsquo;ve been slightly annoyed by the behaviour that the keyboard shortcut in Visual Studio Code didn&amp;rsquo;t open the integrated terminal if I also had an external terminal open, it was switching to that one instead.
Googling the problem didn&amp;rsquo;t help me come closer to an explanation, which I suspected had to do with the language/keyboard specific nature of this issue. As you can see in the image below, the default keyboard shortcut to open the integrated terminal on my machine is Ctrl + ö.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 5 – Costs and Architecture Refection</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-5-costs-and-architecture-refection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 14:58:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-5-costs-and-architecture-refection/</guid><description>Having run my home office monitoring service for more than a month, I can now reflect back on the project. Even though I have an MSDN subscription trough work with a bunch of Azure credit included to spend every month, I decided to use a Pay-As-You-Go subscription for this project. I wanted to be sure that the services I used was available to me even if I would loose the MSDN subscription.</description></item><item><title>Making Cmder Findable by Windows Search</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/making-cmder-findable-by-windows-search/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/making-cmder-findable-by-windows-search/</guid><description>This is just a short reminder for myself. I just found myself reinstalling Windows and thus also my favourite console, Cmder. I didn’t remember what to do to make it findable by Windows search, so here’s how: 1. Add path to environment variable 2. Log off and on again 3. Voilà!</description></item></channel></rss>