<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Backup on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/backup/</link><description>Recent content in Backup on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 14:53:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switching from CrashPlan and other Backup Services</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-from-crashplan-and-other-backup-services/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 14:53:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-from-crashplan-and-other-backup-services/</guid><description>A week before my annual subscription of CrashPlan would expire I got an e-mail informing me that the CrashPlan for Home service was discontinued. My subscription was extended by 60 days to give me enough time to find another service. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it for a couple of years and have been quite happy with it, except maybe for the micro stuttering I experienced. It had the possibility to back up to a local external drive as well as online (offsite) with plenty of configurable options.</description></item><item><title>Micro Stuttering Caused by CrashPlan</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/micro-stuttering-caused-by-crashplan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 06:50:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/micro-stuttering-caused-by-crashplan/</guid><description>For some time I have tried to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s been causing the micro stuttering I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced on my Windows 10 machine. Under moderate load applications have stopped responding for short periods of time, most obvious is audio playback where an unpleasant sound has interrupted playback. I could not see any correlation between this behaviour and a specific application, high CPU, disk or memory utilisation.
My machine is a desktop computer I have built myself from parts, so I thought I might have made some bad decision regarding hardware compatibility.</description></item><item><title>Automatically Backup your Gmail account on a schedule with GMVault and Mac OS X launchd</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/automatically-backup-your-gmail-account-on-a-schedule-with-gmvault-and-mac-os-x-launchd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 21:09:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/automatically-backup-your-gmail-account-on-a-schedule-with-gmvault-and-mac-os-x-launchd/</guid><description>While looking over my backup routines, I stumbled on Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s post Automatically Backup your Gmail account on a schedule with GMVault and Windows Task Scheduler. I had never really thought about backing up my Gmail account, but why not. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m mainly a Windows guy, my Windows 8 machine at home is a big tower that requires quite a lot of electricity and is therefore only powered on when needed.</description></item></channel></rss>