<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows 10 on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/windows-10/</link><description>Recent content in Windows 10 on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 11:22:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/windows-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Frustration with NodeJS on Windows</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/frustration-with-nodejs-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 11:22:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/frustration-with-nodejs-on-windows/</guid><description>During the last couple of years I have noticed more and more developers switching to Mac, especially among those in the SharePoint field that traditionally have been very loyal to Microsoft. I see a correlation between this and the trend away from Visual Studio bound development. After playing around with NodeJS for awhile I understand why and hope for a change. Hopefully I can save you some googling with the links in this post if you run into the same issues as I have.</description></item><item><title>Making Cmder Findable by Windows Search</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/making-cmder-findable-by-windows-search/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 20:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/making-cmder-findable-by-windows-search/</guid><description>This is just a short reminder for myself. I just found myself reinstalling Windows and thus also my favourite console, Cmder. I didn’t remember what to do to make it findable by Windows search, so here’s how: 1. Add path to environment variable 2. Log off and on again 3. Voilà!</description></item><item><title>WinDock Configuration for my 21:9 Screen</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/windock-configuration-for-my-219-screen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 16:59:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/windock-configuration-for-my-219-screen/</guid><description>Hi have recently bought an ultra-wide monitor for my desk at home, a Dell U3415W. I&amp;rsquo;m using it both for work as a coder and for my personal needs such as photo editing, web browsing and watching films. I have previously used a dual monitor setup, so I wanted to find a way of organising windows to be used side-by-side in a productive manner.
figure.lazy {
display: none;
}
Dell U3415W Monitor, 34″ 3440×1440
Dell U3415W Monitor, 34″ 3440×1440
Of course Windows has had the feature to add two windows side-by-side built-in since Windows 7.</description></item><item><title>Lenovo X1 Carbon with Windows 10</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/lenovo-x1-carbon-with-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 09:59:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/lenovo-x1-carbon-with-windows-10/</guid><description>I have recently got the chance to upgrade my work computer from an old, heavy and ugly machine with almost no battery life and a terrible screen to something new and shiny. I ended up getting the third generation Lenovo X1 Carbon (unfortunately without touch screen for budget reasons). This is my experience so far of that machine running Windows 10.
figure.lazy {
display: none;
}
I really like the X1 Carbon.</description></item></channel></rss>