<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/categories/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:02:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Grass is Greener on the Other Side</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/the-grass-is-greener-on-the-other-side/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:02:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/the-grass-is-greener-on-the-other-side/</guid><description>Approaching 40 years old and two years since I changed direction as a software developer, I conclude that the grass really is greener on the other side. Perhaps I should have jumped earlier. Git hooks are better than deployment weekends!</description></item><item><title>Code Quality and Automated Tests for Legacy Systems</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/code-quality-and-automated-tests-for-legacy-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 14:22:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/code-quality-and-automated-tests-for-legacy-systems/</guid><description>My team recently had a discussion trying to agree on a few rules of thumb for our ambition level regarding code quality and automated tests for our legacy systems. These systems are business-critical, but planned to be replaced in a Big Bang fashion.</description></item><item><title>How I Tackled Parental Leave Boredom With Code</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/how-i-tackled-parental-leave-boredom-with-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 04:42:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/how-i-tackled-parental-leave-boredom-with-code/</guid><description>Approaching the end of my parental leave, I&amp;rsquo;ll take a moment reflecting on how I tackled the occasional boredom of a longer absence from work.</description></item><item><title>Yamaha YAS-109 Soundbar has Excessive Network Traffic</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/yamaha-yas-109-soundbar-has-excessive-network-traffic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 11:30:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/yamaha-yas-109-soundbar-has-excessive-network-traffic/</guid><description>This is an appeal to any of you who is coding for, or otherwise developing connected devices, to put some extra thought into your network traffic. Maybe also a warning to consumers and an encouragement to us tech savvy people to monitor your connected devices.</description></item><item><title>Git wasn't that Complicated</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/git-wasnt-that-complicated/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 19:52:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/git-wasnt-that-complicated/</guid><description>When I was about to quit my previous job for the job I have now, I mentioned a few things that I anticipated I would have to learn at the new job. One of the most obvious things was Git&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>There Are Only Temporary Solutions</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/there-are-only-temporary-solutions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 20:14:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/there-are-only-temporary-solutions/</guid><description>This is a reflection from an earlier job I had. It was at one of those large enterprises with monthly deploys and a development process documentation taking up 5 meters on a wall. For 8 years, consultants from one of the largest IT companies, had failed to deliver a company-wide&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Getting a Divorce From SharePoint 💔</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/getting-a-divorce-from-sharepoint/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 23:18:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/getting-a-divorce-from-sharepoint/</guid><description>In my early days as a consultant this product from Microsoft called SharePoint became popular and customers starting to ask for people who could work with it. As a junior, I jumped onboard and could soon call myself a SharePoint developer, one of the hottest thing in the IT consultant market at the time (around 2007).
This specialisation got me into interesting development projects and I learned a lot. What was initially a hurdle (the horrible API), soon became familiar and an advantage for me compared to colleagues in the business that hadn&amp;rsquo;t got the same exposure to the product.</description></item><item><title>Switching from CrashPlan and other Backup Services</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-from-crashplan-and-other-backup-services/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 14:53:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-from-crashplan-and-other-backup-services/</guid><description>A week before my annual subscription of CrashPlan would expire I got an e-mail informing me that the CrashPlan for Home service was discontinued. My subscription was extended by 60 days to give me enough time to find another service. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it for a couple of years and have been quite happy with it, except maybe for the micro stuttering I experienced. It had the possibility to back up to a local external drive as well as online (offsite) with plenty of configurable options.</description></item><item><title>Micro Stuttering Caused by CrashPlan</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/micro-stuttering-caused-by-crashplan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 06:50:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/micro-stuttering-caused-by-crashplan/</guid><description>For some time I have tried to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s been causing the micro stuttering I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced on my Windows 10 machine. Under moderate load applications have stopped responding for short periods of time, most obvious is audio playback where an unpleasant sound has interrupted playback. I could not see any correlation between this behaviour and a specific application, high CPU, disk or memory utilisation.
My machine is a desktop computer I have built myself from parts, so I thought I might have made some bad decision regarding hardware compatibility.</description></item><item><title>Switching to Franz</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-to-franz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 11:41:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-to-franz/</guid><description>When my desktop application for Facebook Messenger, Messenger for Desktop, wanted me to install an update and I found out that the update wanted to install a web browser extension and otherwise pollute my computer, I uninstalled it.
Having a desktop app can sometimes be convenient, even though it has basically the same functionality as the corresponding web interface. So, I googled and found Franz, a desktop messaging app that supports a bunch of messaging services and is available for Windows, Mac and Linux.</description></item></channel></rss>