<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>macOS on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/macos/</link><description>Recent content in macOS on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 06:22:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MacOS Alternative to Notepad++</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/macos-alternative-to-notepad-plus-plus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 06:22:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/macos-alternative-to-notepad-plus-plus/</guid><description>Having switched from Windows to Mac quite recently, there is one application in particular that I’m missing – Notepad++. After trying Notes and Stickes, Brackets and a bunch of others, I had to rethink what I was actually using Notepad++ for and which characteristics I was appreciating the most.</description></item><item><title>Settings for new MacBook Pro</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/settings-for-new-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 10:22:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/settings-for-new-macbook-pro/</guid><description>I recently bought a new machine, a MacBook Pro 16&amp;quot;, and this is my initial configuration. I&amp;rsquo;m documenting this for my future self so I have something to cherry-pick from if I will ever configure a new Mac from scratch. Some of these things might not be relevant in future versions of macOS or for future versions of myself, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see a point in automating it.</description></item><item><title>I ❤️ My "New" 2013 MacBook Pro</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/i-love-my-new-2013-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 21:29:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/i-love-my-new-2013-macbook-pro/</guid><description>This is a story about my personal computer (PC) experience, from the 1990’s up to my new love for a six year old laptop.
In November 2019 my wife bought a new laptop (MacBook Air) and I took over the old one. It’s a 2013 MacBook Pro that I have borrowed a few times for debugging web pages on iOS, but beyond that I don’t have much macOS experience. I saw the opportunity to take it and learn macOS for real for the first time.</description></item><item><title>Bypassing a Corporate Proxy</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bypassing-a-corporate-proxy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 09:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bypassing-a-corporate-proxy/</guid><description>Quite a few organisations seems to find this thing called “Internet” a scary thing that employees can only be given access to by grace of the mighty network administrators. As a consultant I have worked for a few of those organisations and felt the frustration when a blog is blocked or network traffic is so slow that you&amp;rsquo;d guess that it&amp;rsquo;s manually monitored before accepted. I would personally never try to bypass these controls of course, but hypothetically one could do like the following.</description></item><item><title>Automatically Backup your Gmail account on a schedule with GMVault and Mac OS X launchd</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/automatically-backup-your-gmail-account-on-a-schedule-with-gmvault-and-mac-os-x-launchd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 21:09:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/automatically-backup-your-gmail-account-on-a-schedule-with-gmvault-and-mac-os-x-launchd/</guid><description>While looking over my backup routines, I stumbled on Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s post Automatically Backup your Gmail account on a schedule with GMVault and Windows Task Scheduler. I had never really thought about backing up my Gmail account, but why not. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m mainly a Windows guy, my Windows 8 machine at home is a big tower that requires quite a lot of electricity and is therefore only powered on when needed.</description></item></channel></rss>