<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Internet of Things on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/internet-of-things/</link><description>Recent content in Internet of Things on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 11:30:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/internet-of-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yamaha YAS-109 Soundbar has Excessive Network Traffic</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/yamaha-yas-109-soundbar-has-excessive-network-traffic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 11:30:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/yamaha-yas-109-soundbar-has-excessive-network-traffic/</guid><description>This is an appeal to any of you who is coding for, or otherwise developing connected devices, to put some extra thought into your network traffic. Maybe also a warning to consumers and an encouragement to us tech savvy people to monitor your connected devices.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 5 – Costs and Architecture Refection</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-5-costs-and-architecture-refection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 14:58:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-5-costs-and-architecture-refection/</guid><description>Having run my home office monitoring service for more than a month, I can now reflect back on the project. Even though I have an MSDN subscription trough work with a bunch of Azure credit included to spend every month, I decided to use a Pay-As-You-Go subscription for this project. I wanted to be sure that the services I used was available to me even if I would loose the MSDN subscription.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 19:03:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration/</guid><description>This is a summary post of my exploration of Internet of Things. A small hobby project I have used to learn new technologies slightly outside my comfort zone.
My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure My IoT Exploration – Part 2 – Raspberry Pi Sense HAT My IoT Exploration – Part 3 – Sending Data to Cloud My IoT Exploration – Part 4 – Presenting the Data My IoT Exploration – Part 5 – Costs and Architecture Refection</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 4 – Presenting the Data</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-4-presenting-the-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 18:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-4-presenting-the-data/</guid><description>This is my fourth post about exploring Internet of Things, previous posts can be found here:
My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure My IoT Exploration – Part 2 – Raspberry Pi Sense HAT My IoT Exploration – Part 3 – Sending Data to Cloud For the last piece of this project I pretty much followed the approach described in Visualizing IoT Data with Web App. Since I wanted to learn how to create and deploy Azure Web Apps, this was a good fit.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 3 – Sending Data to Cloud</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-3-sending-data-to-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:48:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-3-sending-data-to-cloud/</guid><description>In part 3 of my IoT exploration I connect my Raspberry Pi to Azure IoT Hub and create a NodeJS app that relays data from my Python program to Azure.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 2 – Raspberry Pi Sense HAT</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-2-raspberry-pi-sense-hat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 05:38:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-2-raspberry-pi-sense-hat/</guid><description>Continuing my Internet of Things journey from my earlier post My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure, I got a Raspberry Pi with a Sense HAT. The Sense HAT has all the features I need, integrated in one shield: temperature, humidity and barometric pressure and a LED as a bonus. Given my goal that I wanted to push the data to a hosted service, I now had a much better foundation for succeeding with that.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-1-the-failure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 17:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-1-the-failure/</guid><description>Last Christmas I got an Arduino starter kit for present. It took me a long time to finally open the box and have an idea about what I should do with it. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found challenging about learning new stuff that I don&amp;rsquo;t have an immediate use for, is the lack of a clear goal. Making an LED blink isn&amp;rsquo;t all that exiting in my mind and even though I like the projects in the starter kit, I didn&amp;rsquo;t do them until I had a project of my own figured out.</description></item></channel></rss>