<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TypeScript on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/typescript/</link><description>Recent content in TypeScript on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:20:10 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/typescript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gatsby Source Plugin for Twitter</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/gatsby-source-plugin-for-twitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:20:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/gatsby-source-plugin-for-twitter/</guid><description>I was rewriting a WordPress site in Gatsby that had embedded tweets using an embed script (WordPress plugin). The product owner (my wife), required the new site to also show her tweets. I didn’t like the idea of an embed script (that would slow down the site and spy on visitors), so I started to look into Gatsby source plugins.</description></item><item><title>Using Angular HTTP Interceptor for Logging</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/using-angular-http-interceptor-for-logging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 11:35:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/using-angular-http-interceptor-for-logging/</guid><description>A thing we&amp;rsquo;ve found handy in the Angular application I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on, is the console logging of HTTP requests and responses. This makes it quick to determine if a problem exists in the Angular app or in the REST service we&amp;rsquo;re calling (that we develop alongside the Angular app). Since logging it this way will show exactly which method is being called, the data being sent, headers and everything you need, there is no risk of mistaking one server interaction with another one.</description></item><item><title>Code Sharing with Multi-App Angular Project Using Base Components</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/code-sharing-with-multi-app-angular-project-using-base-components/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 11:51:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/code-sharing-with-multi-app-angular-project-using-base-components/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m building a new version of a web shop in Angular that should be used on three different web sites for three of my client&amp;rsquo;s subsidiary companies. In the current solution, everything but the CSS is common, even the HTML. That has proven to lack the necessary flexibility when the different subsidiaries have different needs and their design agencies are told that they are not allowed change the mark-up. Every change also has to be approved by all three subsidiaries, which takes time.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 3 – Sending Data to Cloud</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-3-sending-data-to-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 08:48:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-3-sending-data-to-cloud/</guid><description>In part 3 of my IoT exploration I connect my Raspberry Pi to Azure IoT Hub and create a NodeJS app that relays data from my Python program to Azure.</description></item></channel></rss>