<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arduino on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/arduino/</link><description>Recent content in Arduino on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 16:17:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/arduino/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Difference between Arduino and Raspberry Pi for a High-Level Programmer</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/difference-between-arduino-and-raspberry-pi-for-a-high-level-programmer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 16:17:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/difference-between-arduino-and-raspberry-pi-for-a-high-level-programmer/</guid><description>Before I got an Arduino for Christmas I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about it. I had heard about Raspberry Pi though, and I was told that it was roughly the same thing.
It&amp;rsquo;s true that the two devices have some common characteristics, but to me the differences are fundamental. As someone who does high-level programming for a living, I am appealed by the idea of being able to read values from analogue sensors in my code, and the plethora of sensors available for the Arduino is impressive.</description></item><item><title>My IoT Exploration – Part 1 – The Failure</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-1-the-failure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 17:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/my-iot-exploration-part-1-the-failure/</guid><description>Last Christmas I got an Arduino starter kit for present. It took me a long time to finally open the box and have an idea about what I should do with it. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found challenging about learning new stuff that I don&amp;rsquo;t have an immediate use for, is the lack of a clear goal. Making an LED blink isn&amp;rsquo;t all that exiting in my mind and even though I like the projects in the starter kit, I didn&amp;rsquo;t do them until I had a project of my own figured out.</description></item></channel></rss>