<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WordPress on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/wordpress/</link><description>Recent content in WordPress on Henrik Sommerfeld's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 21:25:57 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/tags/wordpress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switching from WordPress to Hugo</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 21:25:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/switching-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid><description>I have recently migrated my blog from WordPress to Hugo. That is, switching from a database-based web content management system with loads of themes, plugins and a large user base to a statically generated site with no server-side logic and a small feature set where I must build most things myself.
The switch was by no means necessary, I had cheap hosting at a web hotel I will still use for other sites after the migration, speed was good with WP Super Cache and so on.</description></item><item><title>Bundling resources from plug-ins in my WordPress theme</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bundling-resources-from-plug-ins-in-my-wordpress-theme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 20:02:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/bundling-resources-from-plug-ins-in-my-wordpress-theme/</guid><description>Some time ago I got the idea to ramp up my skills in front-end web development and the tooling used outside my own world of SharePoint. I decided to create my own WordPress theme, but use as much of existing tooling and templates as I could.
Sage got my attention, so I downloaded that and started to look into its components. This was all new territory for me with Bower, Gulp, PHP, NodeJS and so on.</description></item><item><title>Using a Responsive CSS Grid with Relative Measures</title><link>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/using-a-responsive-css-grid-with-relative-measures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 17:05:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.henriksommerfeld.se/using-a-responsive-css-grid-with-relative-measures/</guid><description>When you build a web site on a [CMS][1] and a theme made by someone else you always have some limitations. For this blog I use WordPress and the [Montezuma theme][2], and this is how I customised the default CSS grid options to my liking.
figure.lazy {
display: none;
}
These are the grid options you can choose from in version 1.2.4 of the Montezuma theme.</description></item></channel></rss>